E. Adamson Hoebel Papers 1925-1983 Mss.Ms.Coll.43
American Philosophical Society
E. Adamson Hoebel Papers
1925-1993
Mss.Ms.Coll.43
American Philosophical Society
11.75 Linear feet
Edward Adamson Hoebel (1906-1993) was an anthropologist and educator best known for his studies of the legal systems of pre-literate societies. Graduating from Columbia, where he had studied with Ralph Linton, Franz Boas, and Ruth Benedict, Hoebel early became a scholar on the legal cultures of the Plains Indians, including the Comanches and Cheyennes. After appointments at New York University and the University of Utah, he spent the majority of his academic career at the University of Minnesota, from which he became emeritus professor in 1972. The E. Adamson Hoebel Papers (1925-1993) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hoebel, papers by colleagues and students, Hoebel's research notes, course materials, and photographs.
Hoebel, E. Adamson (Edward Adamson), 1906-1993
Bibliography
Hoebel, E. Adamson, Anthropology and the Human Experience, 5th ed. (New York: McGraw Hill, 1979). Call no.: 572 H67a
Cohoe, A Cheyenne sketchbook, commentary by E. Adamson Hoebel and Karen Daniels Petersen (Norman: University of Oklahoma, 1964). Call no.: 970.3 C66c
K.N. Llewellyn and E. Adamson Hoebel, The Cheyenne Way: conflict and case law in primitive jurisprudence (Norman: University of Oklahoma, 1961). Call no.: 970.3 L77
Ernest Wallace and E. Adamson Hoebel, The Comanches: Lords of the South Plains (Norman: University of Oklahoma, 1952). Call no.: 970.3 W15c
E. Adamson Hoebel, Man in the Primitive World: An Introduction to Anthropology (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1949). Call no.: 572 H67m
Accruals note
Addition of Sept. 16, 1994: Approximately 1 linear foot of correspondence with business associates and fellow anthropologists (1920s-1990s; bulk:1928-1945). Also included are notes Hoebel used for his doctoral dissertation on the Comanche Indians (1930s) and materials regarding the planning of the first summer training institute of the Social Science Research Council, which was held at the Harvard School of Law (1955). One linear foot of textbooks and articles written by Hoebel were donated with the manuscript materials, which have been transferred to the Printed Materials Department.
Addition of November 1995: Included correspondence, information on the Handbook of North American Indians, works by Hoebel, and works by others. ca. 30 items (1960s-1990s).
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Hoebel Papers were donated to the APS Library by E. Adamson Hoebel in 1985 (Accession 1985-924ms) and in 1987 (Accession 1987-1563ms). After his death, additions were made to the collection through the estate of E. Adamson Hoebel in 1993 (Accession 1993-1749ms), 1994 (Accession 1994-771ms), and 1995 (Accession 1995-960ms and Accession 1995-1180ms).
Scope and Contents note
The E. Adamson Hoebel Papers (1925-1993) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Hoebel, papers by colleagues and students, research notes by Hoebel, course material, and photographs, which document Hoebel's career as an anthropologist.
The papers (26 boxes; 14 linear feet) are divided into seven series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1925-1993 (9 boxes; 4.5 linear feet)
Series II. Subject Files, 1927-1993 (4 boxes; 2.0 linear feet)
Series III. Works by Hoebel, 1927-1987 (4 boxes; 2.0 linear feet)
Series IV. Works by Others, 1934-1991 (2 boxes; 0.5 linear feet)
Series V. Research notes, 1932-1950 (9 boxes; 4.75 linear feet)
Series VI. Course materials, 1930s-1980 (2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet)
Series VII. Photographs, 1928-1976? (1 box; 0.25 linear feet)
Series II. Oversized materials (4 boxes; 2.0 linear feet)
Oversized materials follow the same series arrangement as noted above. Cross referencing to oversized material appears on the folders in the standard sized boxes. All photographs and negatives have been removed from Series I-VI and placed in Series VII. Cross references appear in the original series. Reprints have been moved to the printed materials collection of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place. To retrieve reprints, consult the card catalog for printed materials.
Biographical/Historical note
Edward Adamson Hoebel (1906-1993) was an anthropologist and educator best known for his studies of the legal systems of pre-literate societies. Hoebel was born 16 November 1906 in Madison, Wisconsin. His father, Edward Charles Gilbert Hoebel, was vice president of Madison Saddlery Company; his mother, Kathryn Arnold, served as the Civil Service Commissioner for the state of Wisconsin. Hoebel received his undergraduate education in sociology and economics at the University of Wisconsin in 1928. After studying for a year as an American Exchange Fellow at the Universität Köln, Hoebel earned his master's degree at the New York University in 1930. His thesis was titled "Home Conditions and Delinquency Among Adolescent Boys."
Hoebel began his ground-breaking work in primitive law as a doctoral student at Columbia University, originally under the direction of Franz Boas and Ruth Benedict. However, when Hoebel expressed an interest in doing dissertation research on the legal systems of the Plains Indians, he noted that his advisors' reactions were typical of the anthropological views of primitive law at that time: "Franz Boas could tell me...that aboriginal American Indian tribes had no law. Ruth Benedict could simply say, 'I know nothing about it.'" (Ser. III, The American Behavioral Scientist--Preface, Nov. 1981) Boas put Hoebel in contact with Karl N. Llewellyn, Betts Professor of Law at Columbia. Llewellyn, a legal realist who believed that the heart of law is in how a society actually handles disputes rather than in written legal codes per se, was interested in Hoebel's ideas and agreed to serve as his advisor. Hoebel did field research on Comanche legal systems at the Santa Fe Laboratory of Anthropology (Ralph Linton, director), and his dissertation findings were published in an article titled "The Political Organization and Law-ways of the Comanche Indians." In 1934, Hoebel received his PhD degree in anthropology.
After graduation from Columbia, Hoebel and Llewellyn continued their fruitful collaboration, a relationship that established a model for interdisciplinary studies in law and anthropology. Together they developed the trouble-case method for investigating the legal systems of non-literate societies, which they presented in The Cheyenne Way: Conflict and Case Law in Primitive Jurisprudence (1941). Central to this method was the concept of law-jobs, which operate regardless of whether a legal system is considered primitive or advanced. To Hoebel, as well as to many legal scholars, the ideas presented in The Cheyenne Way suggested applications to the legal systems of contemporary literate societies. Hoebel pursued such a line of research in his studies of Pakistan's legal systems and through his involvement in activities such as the World Law Project, a pilot study that sought to compare legal systems throughout the world.
In addition to his field research, Hoebel contributed to anthropology as an educator, both as a teacher and as a writer. From 1929 until 1948 Hoebel taught sociology and anthropology at New York University, where he attained the rank of assistant professor. For the next six years he was professor and head of the anthropology department at the University of Utah. Hoebel served as Dean of Arts and Sciences during his last year at Utah (1953-1954), his only venture into university administration. While at the University of Utah, Hoebel published his first undergraduate textbook, Man in the Primitive World: An Introduction to Anthropology (1949). This highly successful and widely used text was translated into seven languages and updated in subsequent editions.
From 1954 until 1968, Hoebel chaired the anthropology department at the University of Minnesota, during which time he added ten new faculty members to the department. In keeping with his strong commitment to undergraduate education, Hoebel instituted a departmental policy requiring all professors to teach introductory sections to ensure that the student's first encounter with anthropology was a good one. In 1966, Hoebel published his second major introductory textbook, Anthropology: The Study of Man. That same year, the University of Minnesota honored him with the title of Regents Professor, the highest award given to faculty members. Hoebel remained actively involved at the University of Minnesota until 1972, after which time he continued as emeritus and adjunct professor of law.
Hoebel's academic career included several visiting professorships at the universities of Harvard, Chicago, Nijmegen, Arizona, and Lehigh. Concurrent with his academic work, Hoebel participated in several projects that applied anthropological theories and methods to contemporary problems. During the summer of 1944, Hoebel served as community analyst for the War Relocation Authority at the Granada Relocation Center in Amache, Colorado. In that capacity, he facilitated the reassimilation of evacuees into American life. Between 1943 and 1949, Hoebel worked with Llewellyn to study the law-ways of the Pueblo Indians of New Mexico. Through these studies, Hoebel and Llewellyn were able to assist the Pueblo Indians in framing their legal codes in a way that would be understandable and acceptable in federal and state courts. Hoebel's other nonacademic service included consulting as a special officer of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency (1969-1973), as well as participating in the development of specialized research and training programs of the National Science Foundation, the National Institutes of Health, and the Social Science Research Council.
Hoebel received wide recognition for his many contributions to the field of anthropology. His papers include letters of appreciation from his students, many of whom continued to correspond with him throughout their careers. Hoebel's professional colleagues elected him president of the American Ethnological Society from 1946-1947 and of the American Anthropological Association from 1956-1957. In 1963, he became a member of the American Philosophical Society. Hoebel died in 1993, survived by his wife Irene and his son, Bartley Gore Hoebel, a psychology professor at Princeton University.
Adams, Richard E. W., 1931-; American Anthropological Association.; Beals, Ralph L. (Ralph Leon), 1901-1985; Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1848; Blumer, Herbert, 1900-1987; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942; Chiba, Masaji, 1919-; Du Bois, Cora Alice, 1903-; Eggan, Fred, 1906-1991; Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005; Frost, Everett; Gluckman, Max, 1911-1975; Goldfrank, Esther Schiff; Gravel, Pierre Bettez; Hsu, Francis L. K., 1909-; Llewellyn, Karl N. (Karl Nickerson), 1893-1962; Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Nicholson, Maggi E.R.; Oliver, Douglas L.; Opler, Morris Edward, 1907-1996; Paddock, John; Petersen, Karen Daniels; Science Museum of Minnesota.; United States. War Relocation Authority; van den Steenhoven, Geert; Visscher, Maurice B., 1901-1983; Wallis, Ruth Sawtell, 1895-1978; Arms control; Cheyenne Indians; Comanche Indians; Disarmament.; Field notes.; Fort Hall Indian Reservation (Idaho); Gelatin silver prints; Indians of North America--Idaho; Indians of North America--Wyoming; Interviews; Japanese Americans--Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Law, Primitive; Lectures; Manuscripts (for publication); Nitrate negatives; Photoprints; Plains Indians; Pueblos--New Mexico; Shoshoni Indians; Slides.; Sun-dance
- Series I. Correspondence, 1931-1992; 9 boxes; 4.75 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated during Hoebel's career. Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder. When a correspondence file includes letters to a third party (i.e., not Hoebel), the name is indented under the folder title.
  Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. Enclosed manuscripts have been removed from this series and placed in Series III or IV as appropriate. As with the reprints, a photocopy of the title page was filed with the original letter. Cross references are also given for enclosed photographs, which have been removed to Series VII. Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter.
  Correspondents in Series I include:
  Adams, Richard E.W.
  Beals, Ralph L.
  Blumer, Herbert
  Chiba, Masaji
  Du Bois, Cora
  Eggan, Fred
  Fenton, William N.
  Frost, Everett
  Gluckman, Max
  Hsu, Francis L.K.
  Llewellyn, Karl N.
  Mead, Margaret
  Nicholson, Maggi E. Read
  Oliver, Douglas L.
  Opler, Morris
  Paddock, John
  Petersen, Karen Daniels
  van den Steenhoven, Geert
  Visscher, Maurice B.
  Wallis, Ruth
  Wittfogel, Esther S.
  The bulk of this series covers the 1950s to the 1970s. Correspondents include anthropologists, students, some Native Americans (Juanito Medina), and publishers (McGraw-Hill). Among the topics covered in this series are: Hoebel's affiliations with the American Anthropological Association and the Science Museum of Minnesota; his career at the University of Minnesota; his involvement in the War Relocation Authority; and conferences that he attended.
  - Aborn, Murray, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Acosta, June, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Adair, John (Box 1)
    See Ser.I, Wittfogel, Esther S.
  - Adams, Richard Edward Wood, 1969, 1976-1986 (Box 1)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Jerry, 1967-1972, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Alliance College, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - Alpenfels, Ethel J., 1958 (Box 1)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1938-1974 (Box 1)
    See also Ser.II, same title; Mead, Margaret; Murdock, George P.; Sapir, Edward; Tax, Sol
  - American Anthropologist, 1938-1941, n.d. (Box 1)
    Linton, Ralph
  - American Antiquity, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1970 (Box 1)
  - American Association of Law Schools, 1962 (Box 1)
  - American Bar Foundation, 1968 (Box 1)
  - American Book Company, 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1939, 1947 (Box 1)
  - American Ethnologist, 1977 (Box 1)
  - The American Folklore Society, Inc., 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - American German Student Exchange, Inc., 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - American Indian Culture and Research Journal, 1982, 1984 (Box 1)
  - American Indian Quarterly, 1974 (Box 1)
  - American People's Encyclopedia, 1945 (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Association, 1962 (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1960-1987 (Box 1)
  - The American University, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Amherst College, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Amo, D. Curtis, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Jacquelyn, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Archer, Roger W., 1976-1992 (Box 1)
  - Arensberg, Conrad M., 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Louis G., 1964 (Box 1)
  - Aron, Terry, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Aschenbrenner, Peter J., 1971 (Box 1)
  - Aschenbrenner, Stan E., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Asenap, Herman, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - Ashley-Montagu, M.F., 1938 (Box 1)
  - The Asia Foundation, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Assier-Andrieu, Louis, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Association for Anthropological Diplomacy, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Atheneum Press, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Auerbach, Carl A., 1968, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Baber, Ray E., 1932-1949 (Box 1)
    University of Maine
  - Ball, Jane A., 1979, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Barker, Robert W., 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Barnes and Noble, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Barnett, H.G., 1940 (Box 1)
  - Barnum, Cyrus (Box 1)
    See Ser.III, Barnum, Cyrus--Memorial
  - Barry, J. Neilson, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Beals, Ralph L., 1958-1982 (Box 1)
    Currier, Richard L.; Kaiser, Susan; See also Ser.I, Currier, Richard L.
  - Bean, Atherton, 1972, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Beardsley, Richard K., 1956 (Box 1)
  - Beattie, J.H.M., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Becker, Georg, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    Becker, The
  - Becker, The (Box 1)
    See Ser.I, Becker, Georg
  - Beidelman, Thomas O., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Ruth, 1938, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin, Gail R., 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bentley, Harold W., 1954, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Berea College, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Harold J. (Box 1)
    See Ser.I, Social Science Research Council. Institute in Law and Social Relations
  - Bernheimer, Charles L., 1935-1936 (Box 1)
  - Bicchieri, Marco, 1973, 1981, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Bieder, Robert E., 1970-1975, n.d. (Box 1)
    See also Ser.I, Center for the History of the American Indian; See also Ser.I, Modell, Judy
  - Birdwhistell, Ray L., 1942, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bittle, William E., 1974 (Box 1)
    See also Ser.I, Carlson, Gustav G.
  - Blakeway, Martin, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Blegen, Theodore C., 1958 (Box 1)
  - Blumer, Herbert, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Boas, Franz, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Bodine, Ann, 1979, n.d. (Box 1)
    Currier, Richard L.; See also Ser.I, Currier, Richard L.
  - Boggs, Steve, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bohannan, Paul, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Bolton, Ralph, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Boynton, David P., 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Brand, Elizabeth, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Brandes, Stanley H., 1979-1982 (Box 2)
  - Brawner, Marlyn R., 1973 (Box 2)
  - Bray, Kingsley, M., 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Breckenridge, W.J., 1978 (Box 2)
  - Brew, J.O., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Britt, Steuart Henderson, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Brockman, Albert Daniel, n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Brooklyn Museum, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Brophy, William A., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Anna Vivian, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Stephen W., 1971 (Box 2)
  - Burke, Samuel M., 1960-1983 (Box 2)
    Karamet, U.; See also Ser.I, Lal, Kanwar Prem; See also Ser.I, University of Minnesota
  - Butler, Lucius, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Callis, Helmut G., 1961-1962 (Box 2)
  - Cameron, Cate, 1981 (Box 2)
    See also Ser.I, Gatewood, John Brooking
  - Cameron, Donald, 1971 (Box 2)
  - John C. Campbell Folk School, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Cancian, Francesca M., 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Canty, Carol Shannon, 1984, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Beth, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Gustav G., 1935-1988 (Box 2)
  - Carlston, Kenneth S., 1963 (Box 2)
  - Carneiro, Robert L., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Casagrande, Joseph B., 1956-1982, n.d. (Box 2)
    See also Ser.I, Goldschmidt, Walter
  - Caudill, William, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange between East and West, 1963-1967 (Box 2)
    See also Ser.II, same title
  - Center for the History of the American Indian, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    Bieder, Robert E.
  - Chambers, Clarke A., 1960, 1970-1977 (Box 2)
  - Chambers, Robert, 1978, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Chase, Harold, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Chiba, Masaji, 1967-1989, n.d. (Box 2)
    Chiba, Mieko
  - Chiba, Mieko (Box 2)
    See Ser.I, Chiba, Masaji
  - Chronica Botanica, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, Frederick H., 1974-1983 (Box 2)
  - Claremont Colleges, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Cockburn, Michael, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Fay G., 1972-1983, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Julius, 1958, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Saul, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Cohn, Bernard S., 1957, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Colajanni, Antonino, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Colin, David, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Collier, Donald, 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - Collier, Jane Fishburne, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Collura, Patricia, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Commission on the Rights, Liberties, and Responsibilities of the American Indian, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Committee on International Exchange of Persons, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Comparative Studies in Society and History, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, 1954-1961 (Box 2)
  - Coon, Carleton S., 1972 (Box 2)
  - Cooper, John M., 1939 (Box 2)
  - Cottrell, Leonard S., Jr., 1940 (Box 2)
  - Council for the Study of Mankind, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Alfred R., 1949 (Box 2)
  - Crocombe, Ron G., 1965, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Crow, Ev Tough, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Current Anthropology, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Currier, Richard L., 1975-1983 (Box 2)
    Beals, Ralph L.; Bodine, Ann; Eggan, Fred; Hsu, Francis L.K.; Kirsch, Anthony Thomas; Lancaster, Jane B.; Scholte, Bob; See also Ser.I, Beals, Ralph L.; See also Ser.I, Bodine, Ann; See also Ser.I, Eggan, Fred; See also Ser.I, Foster, George M.; See also Ser.I, Hockett, Charles F.; See also Ser.I, Hsu, Francis L.K.; See also Ser.I, Kirsch, Anthony T.; See also Ser.I, Lancaster, Jane B.; See also Ser.I, Scholte, Bob; See also Ser.I, Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research
  - Currier, Susan K. (Box 2)
    See Ser. I, Kaiser, Susan
  - Dandler-Hanhart, Jorge, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Data-Guide, Inc., 1961-1966 (Box 2)
  - Davitt, Thomas E., 1964 (Box 2)
  - de Laguna, Frederica, 1941 (Box 2)
  - De Micheli Consonni, Cristina, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
  - Dermen, Judith de Ponceau, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Dernen, Diran, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Desai, A.R., 1968-1971 (Box 2)
  - Deutschen Gesellschaft Für Soziologie, 1947 (Box 2)
    in German
  - Diamant, Philip, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Dickey, Anthony, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Dingman, Helen H., 1931 (Box 2)
  - di Salvatore, Elen, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Dittmer, C.G., 1940, n.d. (Box 2)
    See also Ser.I, New York University; See also Ser.I, The University of Wisconsin
  - Dobyns, Henry F., 1968, 1973 (Box 2)
  - William H. Donner Foundation, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Dow Chemical Company, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Downing, Theodore E., 1979-1980 (Box 2)
  - Downs, Sabra W., 1974-1975, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Drucker, Peter F., 1955 (Box 2)
  - Du Bois, Cora, 1976-1982 (Box 2)
  - Dunning, R.W. (Bill), 1960 (Box 2)
  - Durham, G. Homer, 1953, 1955, 1964 (Box 2)
    See also Ser.I, University of Utah
  - Dworkin, Rochelle, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Dwyer, Daisy Hilse, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Ediger, Theodore A., 1940 (Box 3)
  - Edwards, McCoy, and Kennedy, 1991 (Box 3)
  - Eggan, Fred, 1944-1985, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Elmendorf, William, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Elwood, Debra, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959-1962 (Box 3)
  - Engel, David M., 1980 (Box 3)
  - Epstein, A.L., 1967-1985, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Esquire, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Esselstyn, T.C., 1947, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
  - Eubank, Lisbeth, 1953 (Box 3)
  - The Explorers Club, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Fairbanks, Robert A., 1976 (Box 3)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt, 1934, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - Fenton, William N., 1947, 1953, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Ferrara, Anthony, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Fikentscher, Wolfgang, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Finch, Ron, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Firth, Raymond, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Fischer, Jack, 1968 (Box 3)
  - The Ford Foundation, 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Fordham University, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Foreman, Harry, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Fort Worth Museum of Science and History, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Fortes, Meyer, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Foster, George M., 1979-1983 (Box 3)
    Currier, Richard L.
  - Fowler, Catherine S., 1969 (Box 3)
  - Fowler, F.C., 1931 (Box 3)
  - Fowler, Manet, 1938-1988, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Francis, E.K., 1949 (Box 3)
  - Franke, Walter, 1942, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
    Franke, Hildi
  - Franke, Hildi (Box 3)
    See Ser.I, Franke, Walter
  - Frankel, Barbara, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Fraser, Donald M., n.d. (Box 3)
  - Freeman, Derek, 1983-1992 (Box 3)
  - W.H. Freeman and Company, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Frees, Joseph W., 1974-1977, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Frontier Nursing Service, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Frost, Everett, 1971-1976 (Box 3)
  - Frost, Ruth, 1974, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Fuller, Varden, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Funk & Wagnalls Company, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Galea'i, Apelu, 1969 (Box 3)
    See also Ser.I, Humphrey, Hubert H.
  - Galloway, Ewing, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Gang, Kenneth M., 1940 (Box 3)
  - Garland, William, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Garland STPM Press, 1979-1982 (Box 3)
  - Gartner, Murray, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Gatewood, John Brooking, 1981-1985 (Box 3)
    See also Ser.I, Cameron, Cate
  - Gebhardt, Th., 1928 (Box 3)
  - Geerings, Paul F., 1985 (Box 3)
  - Gerlach, Luther P., 1983 (Box 3)